George Jr. Langevin West

Bilingual Technical Support Specialist and Data Analyst with 5+ years of experience in Information Technology and Environmental Sciences.

Please send a message for residency and personal contact information

- Technical Support Specialist offering great, heart-centered customer care in both French and English.
- Data Analyst specializing in data transformation, structuring and visualization, with my awesome Excel skills.
- Reliable and positive team leader, confident at public speaking and presenting.
- Proven ability to teach and mentor peers, provide education and outreach. I like seeing people learn, evolve, and grow.

Work Experience

Bilingual Virtual Technical Support Specialist

Xplornet Communications - Woodstock, NB January 2022 to Present

- Delivering great Bilingual technical support and heart-centered customer care to both Francophone and Anglophone speakers.
- Providing advanced troubleshooting for Xplornet's hardware and services, and with third-party hardware and networks as needed.
- Exceeding Key Performance Indices (KPI) for my role.
- Creating detailed notes for every case in Salesforce.
- Taking calls with Avaya OneX and Avaya CTI.
- Excellent grasp of TCP/IP, networking, both wired and wireless.

Information Officer

Elections Canada Federal Elections - Ingleside, ON September 2021 to September 2021

In a one-day contract with Elections Canada:

- Helped guide voters to the proper booths to vote.
- Ensured eligibility of voters prior to letting them vote.
- Provided general help and maintenance around the election building.
- Sanitized commonly used surfaces.
- Ensured satisfaction of voters and made sure voters left with a smile!

Community Development Worker

The United Church of Canada / l'Église Unie du Canada - Cornwall, ON June 2021 to August 2021

Under the Canada Summer Jobs Grant,

- Designed a vibrant and unique Community Garden and Meditative Space.
- Worked both independently and in a team, remotely and on-site.

- Researched food security issues within our local community.
- Collaborated with stakeholders and partners on many aspects of design and implementation.
- Created a property map using QGIS and Remote Sensing for future reference.
- Created building plans for the Community Garden and Meditative Space using various software.
- Created a financial budget for the Projects to be implemented, focusing on cost saving, possible future expansion and durability.
- Completed a detailed project report outlining recommendations, suggestions, advice and needs for implementation of the Projects.
- Designed a time capsule for a future congregation to open.

Student Research Assistant (Intern)

St. Lawrence River Institute of Environmental Sciences - Cornwall, ON April 2021 to May 2021

- Studied the distribution and habitat of an endangered species (Rapids Clubtail).
- Created informative maps through the use of ArcGIS Pro.
- Analyzed, Transformed, Restructured data with Microsoft Excel.
- Created a Visual Field Guide to Riverine Odonates of Central-Eastern Ontario.
- Performed a literature review of current knowledge pertaining to the Rapids Clubtail, using Scrivener and Microsoft Word.
- Learned to perform a Habitat Suitability Index for the Rapids Clubtail.
- Created a visually appealing presentation through the use of Google Slides, Microsoft Powerpoint and Krita
- Presented my research findings in a professional manner to my peers at the River Institute.

Private Linux Tutor

Self employed - Montréal, QC September 2016 to February 2017

- Mentored students at home and taught Bash, Shell Scripting, and general use of Fedora and CentOS.
- Helped build confidence in students and watched them improve their knowledge. I like seeing people succeed!

Information Systems

Lester B. Pearson School Board - Dorval, QC May 2016 to July 2016

- Deployed Windows 7, 10 and Mac OSX across large networks in an institutional setting.
- Diagnosed and repaired staff computers.
- Imaged devices with Norton Ghost and Dell KACE.
- Troubleshooting commercial printers.
- Communicated in a professional manner in the workplace.
- Repaired and maintained computer hardware.
- Protected the network and educational devices from malware.
- Recovered data from malfunctioning hard drives with a bootable Linux stick.

Education

DCS / DEC in Environmental Technology

St. Lawrence College - Cornwall, ON

AEC / DEP or Skilled Trade Certificate in Computing and Networking Support

Pearson Electrotechnology Center - Lachine, QC

2015 to 2016

Secondary School

Place Cartier Adult Education Center - Beaconsfield, QC 2011 to 2012

Skills

- Desktop Windows XP / Vista / 7 / 8.1 / 10 (2 years)
- Debian / Fedora / Ubuntu (6 years)
- Applications Microsoft Office 2007 / 2010 / 2013 / 2016 (Word, Excel, PowerPoint, Outlook, Access) (5 years)
- LibreOffice / OpenOffice (3 years)
- Powershell (Scripting) (Less than 1 year)
- Bash (CLI and Scripting) (2 years)
- Administration Active Directory Domain Services (2 years)
- DNS / DHCP / WDS servers / Deployment (Less than 1 year)
- Users, Groups and Computers (2 years)
- Group Policy / Local Security Policy (2 years)
- Network File and Sharing Services (Less than 1 year)
- NTFS and UNIX Permissions (5 years)
- Networking TCP/IP (1 year)
- Cisco IOS (Less than 1 year)
- Configuring and maintaining Cisco Routers and Switches (Less than 1 year)
- Configuring and maintaining NAT, WLAN, WAP, etc (Less than 1 year)
- · Achievements Created and maintained a complex domain with many computers
- Created a Powershell script to automate the creation of accounts with ADDS
- Deployed Windows 7 Enterprise throughout a network from a WDS server
- SQL / XML (1 year)
- Unix Logs / Systemd (1 year)
- Dell KACE (1 year)
- Microsoft Powerpoint
- Data Entry
- Event Planning
- Microsoft Outlook
- Administrative Experience (2 years)
- Office Management (1 year)
- Laboratory experience (2 years)

- ArcGIS Pro (1 year)
- Minitab (1 year)
- R (Less than 1 year)
- Communication skills (6 years)
- Jira (Less than 1 year)
- Team management (2 years)
- Remote access software (5 years)
- Google Docs (4 years)
- Public (2 years)
- MacOS (2 years)
- Android (2 years)
- iOS (5 years)
- Scrivener (1 year)
- Microscopy (2 years)
- Research (2 years)
- Data Analysis (2 years)
- Statistics (1 year)
- Microsoft Excel (5 years)
- Microsoft Access (1 year)
- Tableau (Less than 1 year)
- Operating Systems (6 years)
- Linux (6 years)
- DNS (3 years)
- Big Data (Less than 1 year)
- Salesforce (1 year)
- QGIS (3 years)

Languages

- French Fluent
- English Fluent
- Español Beginner

Links

https://www.linkedin.com/in/georgejlw/

Awards

Pearson Electrotechnology Center - Adult Learners Week Award

March 2016

My instructors were impressed with my punctuality, perseverance and high marks!

Craig Fletcher Memorial Award

June 2021

The Craig Fletcher Memorial Award is presented annually to a graduate technician who, while maintaining a sound academic record, made a significant contribution to college life and best represents the standard established by the graduating class.

Faculty Award, E. Tech Program

June 2021

This Faculty Award is awarded to a graduate of the Environmental Technician Program who has achieved above average academic performance and who has made a positive contribution to the learning environment.

Certifications and Licenses

CompTIA Security+

October 2016 to October 2019

I learned a lot to help your enterprise with everything security!

Pleasure Craft Operator Card

January 2021 to Present

I can operate a pleasure craft.

Worker Health and Safety Awareness in 4 Steps

February 2020 to Present

I am aware of risks and safety issues that affect people in the workplace.

AODA Customer Service Training

February 2020 to Present

Accessibility for Ontarians with Disabilities Act

February 2020 to Present

I can provide great customer service and care while respecting the rights and dignity of people with disabilities.

Workplace Violence Prevention

February 2020 to Present

I can communicate with people in ways that minimize or prevent the occurence of violent behaviour in the workplace.

WHMIS

February 2020 to Present

I completed my WHMIS 2015 training through St. Lawrence College.

Amateur Radio Operator Certificate (Basic with Honours)

January 2019 to Present

Competency to operate amateur radio communication devices at designated frequencies, including shortwave.

Abloy Protec 2 Training Course

November 2013 to Present

Competency to assemble, service, maintain or repair Abloy Protec 2 High Security Locks.

Ontario G Driver's License

Present

Groups

Dragonfly Society of the Americas

May 2021 to Present

I am a member of the Dragonfly Society of the Americas, and love studying riverine Odonates (Dragonflies and Damselflies).

SLC Alliance

February 2021 to Present

I am a member of St. Lawrence College's vibrant LGBTQIA+ community.

Additional Information

References available upon request.